if you're looking for a new way to
release any frustration you may have at
the moment you might want to consider
getting yourself a slam haul slam balls
can be used for a lot of exercises such
as squats overhead presses and of course
slamming them into just about any
surface imaginable I've been using this
slam ball from living fit for a while
now so today I'm going to spend some
time and break down my experience for
y'all
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review for y'all this time around I've
got a slam ball from living fit in this
video I'm going to tell you everything
you need to know about this product from
the price the features the pros and the
cons and of course who should or maybe
should not add one of these to their
home gym but before I get going with all
of that we've reviewed a lot of
slamballs on barbin.com so if you want
to browse our best list just go and
search bar Bend best slam balls and you
can find out for yourself which one
cracks that number one spot
[Music]
foreign
Bowl well for starters I really like the
texture right here you get a really good
grip you know there's a lot of Slam
balls that are pretty smooth and that's
not the case here and as you start to
sweat you know you're getting into the
nitty-gritty of your workout you're
going to be able to maintain a solid
grip also like how there's a lot of
buying options for you to choose from
whether that be five pounds or even a
hundred pounds that's really nice and
lastly you know I really like how this
ball is designed to absorb impact so you
know it's really not going to bounce
that much
[Music]
now when it comes to those potential
cons you may experience with this slam
ball you know some people may not be too
crazy about the fact that it really
doesn't bounce that much and that kind
of eliminates you doing some rotational
throws into a wall because it's not
really going to bounce back out at you
these balls also have a sand filling on
the inside and I personally think it
stays pretty balanced overall but some
people may not be too crazy about that
you might want to consider a gel filled
slam ball texture is also a personal
preference you know what works for me
may not work for you you know if you
don't like the grip you get right here
there's some other options out there
that are a lot smoother than these are
and lastly you know these are not the
most expensive slam balls on the market
but they're certainly not the cheapest
so if you're wanting to save some money
you can definitely find some cheaper
ones out there
foreign
[Music]
speaking of money there's a lot of
buying options once again on the living
fit website when it comes to these slam
balls the cheapest one is going to be
that five pound options right around 30
bucks a 20 pounder we have right here is
about 60 bucks 50 pound option is around
130 dollars and that hundred pound ball
it's gonna cost you about 230 bucks now
that's not cheap by any means necessary
these are more on the higher end of
things compared to the rest of the
market there's still some companies like
Rogue that are going to charge about 20
bucks or so more for their slam balls
now considering the quality and the
amount of workouts you're going to get
in with these slam balls I think this is
a pretty good option if you want to save
some money now you can definitely find
some cheaper ones that are out there but
once again considering the high quality
of this product you know I'm not worried
about it breaking down on me anytime
soon so I think it's gonna be worth the
money
foreign
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features you're going to
find with these slam balls obviously you
know this is a slam ball it has a rubber
outside right here it's got a sand
filling you know there's some slam balls
that have a gel filling some people
think those stay you know balanced
better but honestly I haven't had any
problems with this Lambo I don't really
think you will either you have a really
nice grip right here in my opinion it's
a triangular pattern all the way around
it good texture you're going to maintain
a good grip throughout your workouts the
diameter of each slam ball is going to
be directly impacted by the weight
option that you're working with so the 5
to 20 pound slam balls have a nine inch
diameter the 25 to 60 pound options have
an 11 inch diameter and the 70 to 100
Pounders those have a 13 inch diameter
foreign
do a quick walk around now with this
slam ball with the 20 pound version you
know you can see it right here clear as
day that's really nice if you purchase
more than one you know which one is
which now I really like the texture
pattern right here it's triangular
pattern gives me a really good grip you
know my hands start to sweat a lot as
I'm working out I've told y'all that
before and I don't really lose my grip
with this ball and that's obviously
really important when you're you know
doing any type of Slam ball workout now
this is a sand filled ball and not
everybody's crazy about that I don't
really have any issues with it I haven't
really noticed any type of you know
unevenness in terms of the distribution
of weight but I definitely get it while
some people would worry about that and
on the back right here
looks like you have a little pump you
know you could you know you're all
classic you know bicycle pump for your
uh for your tires you just slide a
little needle in there and it starts to
get flat on you I'm guessing that's what
that's for now I don't think you have to
really worry about that now once again
you know this is meant to absorb the
shock so it's not really going to bounce
at you so in terms of rotational throws
you really don't want to do that
[Music]
okay so who's your purchase one of these
slam balls from living fit well if you
are in fact searching the market for a
high quality slam ball it's going to get
the most bang for your buck possible I
think this is a really good option for
you to consider if you get pretty sweaty
hands as you're working out I think
you're really going to like the texture
found right here it's going to allow you
to keep a really solid grip as you're
working out and since there's so many
buying options for you to choose from
chances are there's a weight option out
there that's going to fit your needs
[Music]
okay so what about the people who might
not want to purchase one of these slam
balls well let's talk about the filling
you know once again these have a sand
filling and sometimes people complain
about you know the ball not staying
balanced in terms of weight distribution
so you know if that's something you're
worried about I'd suggest checking out
some gel filled slam balls instead
texture is also a personal preference
you know what works for somebody may not
work for somebody else so if you want a
slam ball that doesn't have as grippy of
a feeling you know there's some smoother
options out there and lastly is really
just the money you know once again these
aren't the most expensive slam balls on
the market but they're definitely not
the cheapest so if you want to save some
money you know go down to more budget
friendly route you can definitely do
that
foreign
over the living fit slam balls I
personally think slam balls are a great
tool for functional training and can be
a great low impact cardio workout as
well I really like the texture of these
slam balls it's going to provide me a
solid grip throughout the duration of my
workout and since they're high quality I
think I'm gonna be tossing this bad boy
around for quite some time there's a lot
of buying options for you to choose from
and I think it's a pretty good deal but
you know there's some people out there
that may not want to show out the
necessary cash needed to add one of
these to their home gym but if you do I
don't think you'll be disappointed
thanks for hanging out with me everybody
I hope this video was really helpful and
I was able to answer any questions you
may have about these slam balls as
always stay posted for my next video but
for now head over to barbin.com and you
can read more about this product just
search bar Bend livingfit slam ball
review you can find all the details I
talked about here today I'll catch y'all
next time
foreign
[Music]